Stafford, Ronald B.; Papers apap217
M.E. Grenander Department of Special Collections & Archives
Ronald B. Stafford Papers
1956-2002
M.E. Grenander Department of Special Collections & Archives
apap217
86.56 cubic ft.
The Ronald B. Stafford Papers document Stafford's service as a New York State Senator representing the 45th District.
Access
Access to this record group is unrestricted with the exception of select folders in Series 1 and 11, which are marked.
Acquisition Information
The Ronald B. Stafford Papers were donated by Kay Stafford to the M.E. Grenander Department of Special Collections and Archives in 2006.
Biographical Sketch
Ronald B. Stafford was born in Plattsburgh, NY, on June 29, 1935. He was the adopted child of Agnes and Halsey Stafford, a grade-school teacher and a state prison worker, and was raised in Dannemora, NY. After graduating from Plattsburgh High School, Stafford earned a B.A. in government from St. Lawrence University in 1957. He served in the U.S. Army as an intelligence officer and earned his J.D. from Columbia School of Law in 1962. He was the first St. Lawrence graduate to be awarded an Edward John Noble Fellowship.
Initially selected by local Republican leaders to run in a special election in 1965, Stafford won his first election to the New York State Senate in 1966. He represented the 45th Senate District in New York State's North Country, which eventually came to include Clinton, Essex, Franklin, Hamilton, Warren, and Washington Counties. Stafford continued to serve the 45th district as State Senator until his retirement in 2002. During his 37-year tenure, Stafford served as Deputy Majority leader for Legislature Operations and as Chairman of several committees including the Senate Judiciary Committee, the Committee on Codes, the Senate Higher Education Committee, and the Senate Finance Committee. While Chairman of the Higher Education Committee in 1974, Stafford helped establish New York State's Tuition Assistance Program (TAP) which provides need-based assistance to many undergraduate students who would otherwise be financially unable to attend college
Senator Stafford was instrumental in bringing the Winter Olympic Games to Lake Placid in 1980, having been appointed Chairman of the New York State 1980 Olympic Winter Games Commission in 1974. He is also noted for his support for the "Toxic Torts Bill," passed in 1986, which expanded legal protection to people exposed to toxic chemicals; Stafford opposed his fellow Republicans during the five-year battle to pass this bill.
As his district included a significant portion of the Adirondack Park, much of his attention was spent representing the needs of the Park and its residents. Governor George Pataki recognized Senator Stafford "for his tireless advocacy on behalf of the people of the Park" in his keynote address at the Adirondack Park Agency's 30th Anniversary in 2003.
Stafford served on several boards during his career, including the Boards of Trustees of the College of St. Rose and St. Lawrence University and the Boards of Directors of the Champlain Valley School of Nursing and the Adirondack Council of the Boy Scouts of America. After his retirement, Governor Pataki appointed him to the Board of Trustees for the State University of New York. Senator Stafford's family included his wife, the former Kay McCabe, two sons, a daughter, a stepson, a stepdaughter, and four stepgrandchildren. He died on June 24, 2005, after battling lung cancer.
Scope and Contents
The Ronald B. Stafford Papers document Stafford's service as a New York State Senator representing the 45th District. The collection represents the wide range of activities in which Stafford engaged during his 37-year tenure in the State Senate. Stafford's legislative activities are represented by a large amount of material on legislation which he sponsored, co-sponsored and supported. His work on behalf of his North Country constituents is represented by documentation of the casework in which his office solved constituents' problems and by letters of support for grant applications. Appointment books and telephone message pads document Senator Stafford's day-to-day activities, and his public accomplishments are recorded in news clippings and press releases. His activities as representative of the Adirondack region are described in series on the Adirondack Park Agency and the Lake Placid Olympics. Senator Stafford's career is further documented by photographs, memorabilia and physical artifacts acquired during his long service in the State Senate.
Arrangement of the Collection
The collection is organized into the following series:
Series 1 - Adirondack Park Agency, 1956-2000, Undated
Series 2 - Lake Placid 1980 Winter Olympics, 1973-1990, Undated
Series 3 - Campaigns, 1974-1992, Undated
Series 4 - Casework, 1976-2002, Undated
Series 5 - Appointment Books, 1972-1996, Undated
Series 6 - Correspondence, 1995-2001
Series 7 - Telephone Messages, 1987-2002
Series 8 - Letters of Support, 1993-2002, Undated
Series 9 - Legislation, 1974-2001, Undated
Series 10 - Summary of Legislation, 1983-2001
Series 11 - Subject Files, 1957-2002, Undated
Series 12 - Photographs, 1981-2002, Undated
Series 13 - Press Releases, 1970-1988
Series 14 - News Clippings, January 22, 1982-November 25, 1990, Undated
Series 15 - Audiovisual Material, 1967-2002, Undated
All series are arranged chronologically with the exception of Series 1 and 2, Series 6 subseries 1, and Series 11 and 12 which are arranged alphabetically.
Public Servants; Politics and Politicians; Education; Conservation and the Environment; Athletics and Sports; Winter Olympics.; Tuition--Law and legislation; Olympic Winter Games (13th: 1980: Lake Placid, N.Y.); New York (State)--Politics and government; Legislation; Case files; Campaigns; Correspondence; Press Releases; Photographs; Stafford, Ronald B.; New York (State). Legislature. Senate; Adirondack Park Agency (N.Y.); Lake Placid Olympic Organizing Committee
- Adirondack Park Agency, 1956-2000; Undated; 1; 3.40 cubic ft.
  Arrangement
  Arranged alphabetically.
  Scope and Contents
  The files in this series pertain to the creation and work of the Adirondack Park Agency (APA) and to the various political groups and legislative bills which supported or opposed the creation of the Agency. The series includes publications by the APA and other groups, legislative files, correspondence, maps, memoranda, and news clippings. The bulk of the series covers the years 1967-1978 and 1990-1997, with some materials dating from 1956-2002. Legislation pertaining to the Adirondack Park Agency can also be found in Series 9 of this collection.
  - Adirondack Advocate, 1993 (Oversized 1, Folder 4)
  - "Adirondack Congress R.B.S", 1993-1998 (Box 1 (1-Adirondack Park Agency), Folder 1)
  - Adirondack Conservation Council, 1969-1970; 1973 (Box 1 (1-Adirondack Park Agency), Folder 2)
  - The Adirondack Council "A Gift of Wildness", 1992 (Box 1 (1-Adirondack Park Agency), Folder 3)
  - The Adirondack Council "Managing Growth and Development in Unique, Natural Settings", 1992 (Box 1 (1-Adirondack Park Agency), Folder 4)
  - Adirondack Fairness Coalition, 1990 (Box 1 (1-Adirondack Park Agency), Folder 5)
  - Adirondack Local Government Review and the Adirondack Park Agency Abolishment Bill, 1973-1976 (Box 1 (1-Adirondack Park Agency), Folder 6)
  - Adirondack National Park Debate Newspaper Clippings, 1959-1968 (Box 1 (1-Adirondack Park Agency), Folder 7)
  - Adirondack Park Association, 1956; 1960-1966; Undated (Box 1 (1-Adirondack Park Agency), Folder 8)
  - Adirondack Park Association, 1973-1975 (Box 1 (1-Adirondack Park Agency), Folder 9)
  - Adirondack Park Commission, 1962-1964; Undated (Box 1 (1-Adirondack Park Agency), Folder 10)
  - The Adirondack Park in the Twenty-First Century, 1990 (Oversized 1, Folder 5)
  - Adirondack Park Local Assistance Program, 1976 (Box 1 (1-Adirondack Park Agency), Folder 11)
  - Adirondack Park Magazine Articles, 1995-1999 (Box 1 (1-Adirondack Park Agency), Folder 12)
  - Adirondack Park Press, 1991-1992 (Box 1 (1-Adirondack Park Agency), Folder 13)
  - Adirondack Planning Commission, 1992 (Box 1 (1-Adirondack Park Agency), Folder 14)
  - Adirondack Rivers Newsclippings, 1972-1977; 1981-1989 (Box 1 (1-Adirondack Park Agency), Folder 15)
  - Adirondack Voices, 1991 (Oversized 1, Folder 6)
  - Ambassadors to Bring Action Through Environmental Study (ABATES Program), 1968-1969; 1972 (Box 1 (1-Adirondack Park Agency), Folder 16)
  - Annual Report, 1974 (Box 1 (1-Adirondack Park Agency), Folder 17)
  - The Association for the Protection of the Adirondacks Reports, 1970-1971 (Box 1 (1-Adirondack Park Agency), Folder 18)
  - Constituent Letters RE: Adirondack Park Agency, 1973 January (Box 1 (1-Adirondack Park Agency), Folder 19)
  - Constituent Letters RE: Adirondack Park Agency, 1973 February (Box 1 (1-Adirondack Park Agency), Folder 20)
  - Constituent Letters RE: Adirondack Park Agency, 1973 March (Box 1 (1-Adirondack Park Agency), Folder 21)
  - Constituent Letters RE: Adirondack Park Agency, 1973 April (Box 1 (1-Adirondack Park Agency), Folder 22)
  - Constituent Letters RE: Adirondack Park Agency, 1973 May (Box 1 (1-Adirondack Park Agency), Folder 23)
  - Constituent Letters RE: Adirondack Park Agency, 1973 June (Box 1 (1-Adirondack Park Agency), Folder 24)
  - Correspondence, Adirondack Park as a National Park Proposal, 1967-1968 (Box 1 (1-Adirondack Park Agency), Folder 25)
  - Correspondence, Champlain Valley Heritage Corridor Project, 1997 (Box 1 (1-Adirondack Park Agency), Folder 26)
  - Correspondence, Delay Bill, 1973 (Box 1 (1-Adirondack Park Agency), Folder 27-28)
  - Correspondence, General, 1973; 1979 (Box 1 (1-Adirondack Park Agency), Folder 29)
  - Correspondence, Senator Marchi, 1973 (Box 1 (1-Adirondack Park Agency), Folder 30)
  - Correspondence, Tent Platform, 1971-1976 (Box 1 (1-Adirondack Park Agency), Folder 31)
  - D.E.C., Articles, 1993-1995 (Box 1 (1-Adirondack Park Agency), Folder 32)
  - D.E.C. Commissioners, History, Organization, 1962-1976; 1980-1998; Undated (Box 1 (1-Adirondack Park Agency), Folder 33)
  - D.E.C.- Conserving Open Space in New York State, 1991 (Box 1 (1-Adirondack Park Agency), Folder 34)
  - D.E.C., "Environmental Plan For New York State", 1973 (Box 1 (1-Adirondack Park Agency), Folder 35)
  - D.E.C, Notice of Public Hearing, Air Quality, 1973 (Box 1 (1-Adirondack Park Agency), Folder 36)
  - D.E.C. Notice of Public Hearing, Contaminant Emissions, 1972 (Box 1 (1-Adirondack Park Agency), Folder 37)
  - Development of More Park-Like Signing Standards for Adirondack Park, 1975 (Box 1 (1-Adirondack Park Agency), Folder 38)
  - "Development Patterns in the Adirondack Park, 1967-1987; 1990 (Box 1 (1-Adirondack Park Agency), Folder 39)
  - Donovan, Senator James H., 1975 (Box 1 (1-Adirondack Park Agency), Folder 40)
  - Draft Guideline for Developing a Local Land Use Work Program, 1973 (Box 1 (1-Adirondack Park Agency), Folder 41)
  - Draft Rules and Regulations For Public Hearing Purposes, 1973 (Box 1 (1-Adirondack Park Agency), Folder 42)
  - Finding Common Ground: Conserving the Northern Forest, 1994 (Box 1 (1-Adirondack Park Agency), Folder 43)
  - Forest Preservation and Park Maps, 1967; 1972; Undated (Box 1 (1-Adirondack Park Agency), Folder 44)
  - Forest Preservation Controversy, 1967 (Box 1 (1-Adirondack Park Agency), Folder 45)
  - Forest Preserve Articles and Booklets, 1958-1988; 1990-1997 (Box 1 (1-Adirondack Park Agency), Folder 46)
  - Forest Preserve 100th Anniversary Newspaper Clippings, 1985 (Box 1 (1-Adirondack Park Agency), Folder 47)
  - Environmental Legislation Study Group- SUNY Albany, Undated (Box 2 (1-Adirondack Park Agency), Folder 1)
  - Forest Preserve Centennial Pin, 1985 (Artifact-box 1)
  - The Future of the Adirondack Park, 1970 (Oversized 2)
  - Governor Mario M. Cuomo's Proposals For the Adirondacks, 1991-1992 (Box 2 (1-Adirondack Park Agency), Folder 2)
  - "Governor's Program Bill Proposals For Changes to the Adirondack Park Laws" By C. Ortloff, 1991 (Box 2 (1-Adirondack Park Agency), Folder 3)
  - Harris, Assemblyman Glenn H., 1972; 1976 (Box 2 (1-Adirondack Park Agency), Folder 4)
  - High Peaks Wilderness Management Plan, 1970-2000 (Box 2 (1-Adirondack Park Agency), Folder 5)
  - Inflation Figures, 1980-1994 (Box 2 (1-Adirondack Park Agency), Folder 6)
  - Inter- County Legislative Committee of the Adirondacks, 1974 (Box 2 (1-Adirondack Park Agency), Folder 7)
  - Lake Placid News, 1976; 1985 (Oversized 1, Folder 7)
  - Land Use and Development Plan Map, 1993 (Box 2 (1-Adirondack Park Agency), Folder 8)
  - Land Use and Development Plan Recommendations For Implementations and Map, 1973 (Box 2 (1-Adirondack Park Agency), Folder 9)
  - Land Use and Development Plan Questions and Answers, 1973 (Box 2 (1-Adirondack Park Agency), Folder 10)
  - League For Adirondack Citizens' Rights, Inc., 1975-1976 (Box 2 (1-Adirondack Park Agency), Folder 11)
  - Legislative File, Adirondack Park, 1992-1993 (Box 2 (1-Adirondack Park Agency), Folder 12)
  - Legislation File, Adirondack Park Description and Lands, 1972 (Box 2 (1-Adirondack Park Agency), Folder 13)
  - Legislative File, Adirondack Park Land Use and Development Plan, 1973 (Box 2 (1-Adirondack Park Agency), Folder 14)
  - Legislative File, Adirondack Park Land Use and Development Plan, 1974 (Box 2 (1-Adirondack Park Agency), Folder 15)
  - Legislative File, Adirondack Park Land Use and Development Plan, 1976 (Box 2 (1-Adirondack Park Agency), Folder 16)
  - Legislative File, APA Act to be Incorporated in Environmental Conservation Law (Draft), 1992 (Box 2 (1-Adirondack Park Agency), Folder 17)
  - Legislative File, APA Administration and Park Land Use Plan, 1975 (Box 2 (1-Adirondack Park Agency), Folder 18)
  - Legislative File, Catskill Park State Owned Lands Catskill, 1973 (Box 2 (1-Adirondack Park Agency), Folder 19)
  - Legislative File, Creation of an Environmental Protecting Act, 1993 (Box 2 (1-Adirondack Park Agency), Folder 20)
  - Legislative File, Creation of APA, Limitation of Forest Preserve Lands, Conservation Restrictions, 1971 (Box 2 (1-Adirondack Park Agency), Folder 21)
  - Legislative File, Election of APA members, Local Land Use Programs, 1976 (Box 2 (1-Adirondack Park Agency), Folder 22)
  - Legislative File, Enforcement and Penalties of Violating APA act, Land Use Plan, Appointment of APA Members, 1976 (Box 2 (1-Adirondack Park Agency), Folder 23)
  - Legislative File, Environmental Legislation Correspondence, 1971-1972 (Box 2 (1-Adirondack Park Agency), Folder 24)
  - Legislative File, Environmental Quality Bonds, 1972 (Box 2 (1-Adirondack Park Agency), Folder 25)
  - Legislative File, Environmental Quality Bonds, 1990 (Box 2 (1-Adirondack Park Agency), Folder 26)
  - Legislative File, Establish New Park Management and Assistance, 1976 (Box 2 (1-Adirondack Park Agency), Folder 27)
  - Legislative File, Establish State Wild, Scenic, and Recreational Rivers System, 1971 (Box 2 (1-Adirondack Park Agency), Folder 28)
  - Legislative File, Improvement, Protection, and Community Development of Adirondack Park, 1992 (Box 2 (1-Adirondack Park Agency), Folder 30)
  - Legislative File, Laws of New York, Adirondack Park Agency (Article 27), Undated (Box 2 (1-Adirondack Park Agency), Folder 29)
  - Legislative File, Memorandum, Ann Purdue, 1976 (Box 2 (1-Adirondack Park Agency), Folder 31)
  - Legislative File, Navigation and Vessels, 1973 (Box 2 (1-Adirondack Park Agency), Folder 32)
  - Legislative File, Powers, Duties, and Functions of APA, Single Family Dwellings, 1976 (Box 2 (1-Adirondack Park Agency), Folder 33)
  - Legislative File, Prohibition Against Diminution; Park Description, Creation of APA, 1971 (Box 2 (1-Adirondack Park Agency), Folder 34)
  - Legislative File, Protection and Conservation at Adirondack Park at State and Local Level, 1991-1992 (Box 2 (1-Adirondack Park Agency), Folder 35)
  - Legislative File, Senate Finance Committee Reports, 1994-1995 (Box 2 (1-Adirondack Park Agency), Folder 36)
  - Legislative File, Single Family Dwellings and Mobile Homes, Creation of Adirondack Park Tax District, Park Land Use Plan, 1976 (Box 2 (1-Adirondack Park Agency), Folder 37)
  - Legislative File, Stafford's Adirondack Park Improvement and Development Act, 1991 (Box 2 (1-Adirondack Park Agency), Folder 38)
  - Legislative File, Zoning and Master Planning Amendment, 1975 (Box 2 (1-Adirondack Park Agency), Folder 39)
  - Local Leader's Guide to Land Use Practices by Profs. J. Daly and J. Nolan, 1997; Undated (Box 2 (1-Adirondack Park Agency), Folder 40)
  - Map of Adirondack Park and the Town of Ausable, 1975; Undated (Flat-file 1)
  - Marilyn DuBois, APA Nominees, 1978; Undated (Box 2 (1-Adirondack Park Agency), Folder 41)
  - Model Zoning and Project, 1975 (Box 2 (1-Adirondack Park Agency), Folder 42)
  - New York Environmental Voter's Guide, 1973 (Box 2 (1-Adirondack Park Agency), Folder 43)
  - New York Statewide Comprehensive Recreation Plan - People Resources, Recreation, 1972 (Box 3 (1-Adirondack Park Agency), Folder 1)
  - Opposition, Adirondack Park - Studies and notes re: proposed amendments, 1992 (Box 3 (1-Adirondack Park Agency), Folder 2)
  - Opposition, Adirondack Park Agency, 1976 (Box 3 (1-Adirondack Park Agency), Folder 3)
  - Opposition, Governor Cuomo's Proposed Bill, 1992 (Box 3 (1-Adirondack Park Agency), Folder 4)
  - Opposition, Private Land Use and Development, 1971-1972; Undated (Box 3 (1-Adirondack Park Agency), Folder 5)
  - Park Permits and Press Releases, 1976; Undated (Box 3 (1-Adirondack Park Agency), Folder 6)
  - Preliminary Private Land Use and Development Plan Draft For Public Hearing Purposes, 1972-1973 (Box 3 (1-Adirondack Park Agency), Folder 7)
  - Preliminary Private Land Use and Development Plan For the Adirondack, 1973 (Box 3 (1-Adirondack Park Agency), Folder 8)
  - Preliminary Private Land Use and Development Plan Maps and Master Plan, 1972 (Box 3 (1-Adirondack Park Agency), Folder 9)
  - Press, 1974-1992 (Box 3 (1-Adirondack Park Agency), Folder 10)
  - Press Releases, 1973-1976; 1990 (Box 3 (1-Adirondack Park Agency), Folder 11)
  - Private Land Use and Development Plan, ca. 1973 (Box 3 (1-Adirondack Park Agency), Folder 12)
  - Private Land Use and Development Plan, Government Response, 1973 (Box 3 (1-Adirondack Park Agency), Folder 13)
  - Private Land Use and Development Plan, Public Response, 1972-1973 (Box 3 (1-Adirondack Park Agency), Folder 14-15)
  - Private Land Use and Development Plan, Reports, Releases, and Modifications, 1972-1974 (Box 3 (1-Adirondack Park Agency), Folder 16)
  - Private Property Protection Act, 1993 (Box 3 (1-Adirondack Park Agency), Folder 17)
  - Proposal For Additions to the State Wild, Scenic and Recreational Rivers System, 1975; Undated (Box 3 (1-Adirondack Park Agency), Folder 18)
  - Proposed Amendment to Article 14 of the Constitution, 1965 February 25; Undated (Box 3 (1-Adirondack Park Agency), Folder 19)
  - Reactions to Changes in Newspapers, 1975-1976 (Box 3 (1-Adirondack Park Agency), Folder 20)
  - "A Report On a Proposed Adirondack Mountains National Park", 1967 (Box 3 (1-Adirondack Park Agency), Folder 21)
  - Resolutions, 1997 (Box 3 (1-Adirondack Park Agency), Folder 22)
  - Resolutions From Counties and Municipalities, 1973 (Box 3 (1-Adirondack Park Agency), Folder 23-24)
  - Rules and Regulations, 1974 (Box 3 (1-Adirondack Park Agency), Folder 25)
  - Rules and Regulations Governing the Wild, Scenic and Recreational River System Within the Adirondack Park, 1976; Undated (Box 3 (1-Adirondack Park Agency), Folder 26)
  - Schroon Lake Map, 1990 (Box 3 (1-Adirondack Park Agency), Folder 27)
  - Staff Working Draft No. 1, Model Local Land Use Controls, Undated (Box 3 (1-Adirondack Park Agency), Folder 28)
  - Stafford and the Environmental Fund, 1993 (Box 3 (1-Adirondack Park Agency), Folder 29)
  - Stafford vs. APA Private Land Use Proposal, 1992 (Box 3 (1-Adirondack Park Agency), Folder 30)
  - State Land Master Plan and Map, 1972 (Box 3 (1-Adirondack Park Agency), Folder 31)
  - State of NY Court of Appeals Opinions, 1977 (Box 3 (1-Adirondack Park Agency), Folder 32)
  - Stock, John, 1975 (Box 3 (1-Adirondack Park Agency), Folder 33)
  - Summary of the Rules and Regulations For Interim Project Review, Undated (Box 3 (1-Adirondack Park Agency), Folder 34)
  - Survey, "Future of the Adirondacks," by T. Holmes, 1991 (Box 3 (1-Adirondack Park Agency), Folder 35)
  - Survey of the Effects of the APA's Land Use Program, Undated (Box 3 (1-Adirondack Park Agency), Folder 36)
  - Temporary Study Commission of the Future of the Adirondacks, 1968-1972 (Box 3 (1-Adirondack Park Agency), Folder 37)
  - Temporary Study Commission of the Future of the Adirondacks, 1970-1972 (Box 3 (1-Adirondack Park Agency), Folder 38)
  - Temporary Study Commission on the Future of the Adirondacks Technical Reports, Undated (Oversized 2)
  - Ton-Da-Lay Project, 1972-1973; 1976 (Box 3 (1-Adirondack Park Agency), Folder 39)
  - Transportation in the Adirondack Region, 1969 (Box 3 (1-Adirondack Park Agency), Folder 40)
  - Tug Hill Region, 1974-1976; Undated (Box 3 (1-Adirondack Park Agency), Folder 41)
  - Union College Adirondack State Park Course, 1975; Undated (Box 3 (1-Adirondack Park Agency), Folder 42)
- Lake Placid Olympics, 1973-1990; Undated; 2; 1.15 cubic ft.
  This series contains material related to the various commissions and committees created to prepare for and host the 1980 Winter Olympics in Lake Placid, New York. Such groups include the Lake Placid Olympic Bid Committee, the Temporary State XIII Olympic Winter Games Commission, and the New York State 1980 Lake Placid Olympic Winter Games Commission. Materials represented include reports, correspondence, appointments, memoranda, minutes, finances, and clippings. Where the original order identifies the specific committee responsible for a record, this order has been maintained. Many folders, however, contain papers involving the records of more than one committee, and sometimes the specific committee responsible for a record cannot be identified. In these cases, folders are identified with the generic title of "Olympic Winter Games Commissions." In addition, the heading "Olympic Organizing Committee" designates records pertaining to the Lake Placid's 1980 Olympic Winter Games Organizing Committee and its subcommittees, which include Transportation, Security and Public Affairs. This series contains materials used for Lake Plaid's Olympic bid. Proposals and agreements with architects and contractors can also be found in this series as well as Olympic pins, programs, tickets, and employment information.
  - Agreement Between Owner and Architect (blank), Undated (Box 1 (2-Lake Placid Olympics), Folder 1)
  - Architect Proposals Sent to the Temporary State Commission, 1975; Undated (Box 1 (2-Lake Placid Olympics), Folder 2)
  - The Colonial Mint Proposal for Olympic Fundraising, 1977 (Box 1 (2-Lake Placid Olympics), Folder 3)
  - Correspondence, General, 1974-1975; 1978; Undated (Box 1 (2-Lake Placid Olympics), Folder 4)
  - Creation of and Appointments to the State Commission on Sports and Winter Olympics, 1975-1976 (Box 1 (2-Lake Placid Olympics), Folder 5)
  - Dormitory Authority's Facilities Proposal, 1976 (Box 1 (2-Lake Placid Olympics), Folder 6)
  - Environmental Information Request Submitted by the Adirondack Park Agency, 1975 (Box 1 (2-Lake Placid Olympics), Folder 7)
  - First Report of the Olympic Organizing Committee, 1974-1975 (Box 1 (2-Lake Placid Olympics), Folder 8)
  - Friends of the Lake Placid 1980 Winter Olympics Contribution Request Letter, Undated (Box 1 (2-Lake Placid Olympics), Folder 9)
  - Employment Request and Resumes, 1974-1976 (Box 1 (2-Lake Placid Olympics), Folder 10)
  - Essex County, Olympic County Pin, 1980 (Artifact-box 1)
  - I Love NY Pin, Undated (Artifact-box 1)